Guide to the Yakima Cooperative Association Records 1934-1967
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Yakima Cooperative Association Records
1934-1967
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections Pullman, WA 99164-5610 USA (509) 335-6691 http://www.wsulibs.wsu.edu/masc/ mascref@wsu.edu
Cage 183
Yakima Cooperative Association
1 containers. .5 linear feet of shelf space. 500 items.
Minutes of regular and special executive sessions, minutes of annual meetings, financial reports, articles of incorporation, by-laws, reports and some correspondence of a Yakima farmers'cooperative dealing in petroleum products, farm equipment and supplies. Included is financial correspondence (1934-1938), of its predecessor, Farm Bureau Services, Inc.
The Yakima Cooperative Association was originally incorporated in August, 1934 under the name Farm Bureau Services, Inc. Farm Bureau Services, Inc. was created by a local group of farmers as a non-profit, non-stock cooperative to provide needed merchandise such as petroleum products, farm equipment and general supplies to the farmers of Yakima and Benton Counties. The Farm Bureau Services, Inc. opened its doors for business in May, 1935. The organization was sold to the Yakima Cooperative Association in March, 1938.
The records of the Yakima Cooperative Association contain the minutes and business records of the association for the period 1934-1967.
They were arranged into two series: Minutes and Correspondence. The "Minutes" Series contains minutes of regular and special executive sessions and annual meetings, financial reports, articles of incorporation and by-laws (including by-laws for both organizations), reports and some correspondence. All of the material in the "Minutes" Series has been photocopied from originals retained by the organization. The "Minutes" Series was arranged chronologically and covers the period 1934-1967. A "Correspondence" Series includes financial dealings of the predecessor organization, from the period February, 1936 through May, 1938. The "Correspondence" Series retains its original order, that is, roughly chronological.
This collection is open for research use.
The records of the Yakima Cooperative Association of Yakima, Washington were donated to the Washington State University Library in June, 1977 by Mr. William Lampe of the Association. (77-38)
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Lampe, William. WaPS
Yakima Cooperative Association--Archives; Farm Bureau Services, Inc.
Agricultural cooperative credit associations--Washington (State)--Records and correspondence; Petroleum products--Washington (State)--Yakima--Marketing; Farm equipment--Washington (State)--Yakima--Marketing
Agriculture; Washington (State)
The following section contains a detailed listing of the materials in the collection.
- Minutes of regular and special executive sessions and annual meetings, articles of incorporation and by-laws, financial reports, some correspondence. (Photocopies)
  - Articles of Incorporation, By-Laws and initial advertising/press coverage, 1934-1935; 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - August 14 1934-January 12 1938, 28 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - March 22 1938-December 13 1940, 62 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - January 13-December 31 1941, 22 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - January 9-December 12 1942, 19 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - January 11 1943-February 28 1944, 22 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - December 11 1944-December 29 1950, 45 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - April 2 1951-December 21 1955, 33 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - February 21 1956-December 28 1960, 61 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - January 25 1961-January 26 1967, 87 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Correspondence:
  - February 1936-May 1938, 99 (Box 1, Folder 11)